MADHAVA KOTAGIRI

 \square

madhavakotagiri514@gmail.co

C

(816)-714-8129

Q

Dayton, USA 45420

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Rational System Analyst with 8+ years of experience enhancing operations for organizations through information systems solutions. Proven track record of transforming specific business goals related to growth and efficiency improvements into new system designs. Knowledgeable innovator known for recommending new technologies to enhance existing systems and introduce new systems.

SKILLS

- JavaScript, Java, HL7.
- User Acceptance Testing
- Test Case Scenarios
- Documentation
- MS-Access, DBMS.
- MS-Office, MS Visio, MS Excel (Macros), MS Power Point, Figma, IRise, Jira, MS Teams, HP ALM, Tableau.
- Project Documentation
- Functional specifications
- Technical documentation
- Requirements gathering
- Agile methodology
- Systems Analysis
- Business Process Mapping
- Gap Analysis
- Data Mapping
- HTML and CSS

EDUCATION

University of Central Missouri Kansas City, MO

Master's in Industrial Technology GPA: 3.64

Jawaharlal Nehru University Andhra Pradesh, IN

Bachelor's in Computer Science & Engineering
GPA: 2.87

CERTIFICATIONS

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

Madhava Kotagiri

WORK HISTORY

CareSource - System Analyst
Dayton • 08/2020 - Current

- Worked with Business Clients, Clients and Product owners to comprehend the current framework and the ongoing business interaction and strategies to distinguish inadequacies and regions for development and upgrade
- Experienced with Cases Strategies and Techniques and interaction streams
- Effectively aided the acknowledgment and approval of the narratives by testing the conveyed stories
- Given definite UI Archive to the turn of events and testing group for clear comprehension of the framework
- Coordinated gatherings with the improvement groups to inspire use cases and record them
- Inspire the business prerequisites through a scope of examination procedures, for example, (information stream outlines, succession graph, hole investigation and interaction stream charts)
- Perform Data mapping from NCPDP to ESI
- Co-ordinate with the Onsite and Offshore resources in managing the incidents
- Directed necessity walkthroughs with the turn of events and test groups before the turn of events and testing stages individually, to guarantee that the prerequisites are precisely perceived
- Made and kept up with Necessities Discernibility Network (RTM) to follow specialized prerequisites to their business prerequisites and the experiment to their utilitarian prerequisites
- Effectively took part in the Day to day stand up and Week after week status gatherings
- Facilitate refinement sessions to review the story cards and conduct follow ups on any technical challenges
- Run swagger to verify the Get and post service domains
 - Participate in planning and sizing of the sprint backlogs by the

- PSM, https://www.scrum.org /certificates/993150
- PSO, https://www.scrum.org /certificates/1042311

- product owner
- Plan UAT test plans, experiments and experiments for combination, relapse, and client acknowledgment testing (UAT) to work on in general nature of the framework
- Arranged definite client manuals and led instructional meetings.

NCP Finance - Business Analyst

Dayton • 01/2020 - 07/2020

- Participate and contribute in Vision/Concept/Design reviews for new business processes and enhancements Provides tangible solutions and guidance on issues faced by various stakeholders
- Researched data dialysis errors and worked to rectify errors, allowing the business to make informed decisions and improve operational efficiency
- Translate stakeholder requirements into tangible deliverables such as functional specifications, user cases, user stories, workflow/process diagrams, data flow/data model diagrams
- Draft and maintain business requirements and align them with functional and technical requirements
- Communicate client's business requirements by constructing easy to understand data and process models
- Provide input into developing and modifying systems to meet client needs and develop business specifications to support these modifications
- Liaise between business and technical personnel to ensure a mutual understanding of processes and applications
- Facilitate meetings with clients to document requirements and explore potential solutions
- Create mockups for prototyping various business requirements using balsamiq wireframes
- Work towards resolving various level 2 tickets from the customer service and compliance.

Encore Capital Group - Business System Analyst

San Diego • 02/2018 - 12/2019

- Coordinate with business units to build upon solutions that are strategic, cost effective and meet business requirements; document requirements, functional specifications and coordinate the planning and execution of user acceptance
- · Identify stakeholders and facilitate discussions or workshop with the purpose of eliciting and understanding stakeholders' requirements, priorities, and needs
- Extensively used Agile Methodology in the process of the project management based on SDLC
- Used MS Word & Visio to document data flow of the AS-IS process and TO BE process
- Elicit the business requirements through a range of analysis techniques such as (data flow diagrams, sequence diagram, gap analysis and process flow diagrams)
- Recommend design solutions for technical design constrains to business and work on development and delivery of product for business visions
- Organized meetings with the development teams to elicit use cases and document them
- · Performed UI Design and Analysis, Involved in GUI interfacing and

- prototyping, System Integration testing and created test cases for QA Testing and test scripts
- Actively involved in Scrum Sprint Planning Sessions, Backlog Grooming, Sizing, Sprint Retrospectives & Reviews, Daily Standup, User Stories and Acceptance Criteria
- Design UAT test plans, test cases and test cases for integration, regression, and user acceptance testing (UAT) to improve overall quality of the system
- Coordinate for the final signoff from the business stakeholders
- Lead the business analyst effort in support research stories, mainly focused on Azure
- Use various tools and technologies like; Visio for analysis, design pattern for solutions, irise for prototyping
- Lead various Demo meetings to update the business and stakeholders on the development of product and use of various reporting tools.

GSS Info Tech - Junior Business Analyst

Hyderabad • 09/2014 - 10/2015

- Worked with Business Users, Customers and Subject Matter Experts (SMEs) to understand the existing system and the current business process and methods to identify deficiencies and areas for improvement and enhancement
- Experienced with Claims Policies and Procedures & process flows
- Performed on site Health Plan reviews for Medicaid encounter compliance
- Implemented and maintained all EDI payer files for private, Medicaid and Medicare insurance plans
- Actively assisted in the acceptance and validation of the stories by testing the delivered stories
- Provided detailed User Interface Document to the development and testing team for clear understanding of the system
- Organized meetings with the development teams to elicit use cases and document them
- Elicit the business requirements through a range of analysis techniques such as (data flow diagrams, sequence diagram, gap analysis and process flow diagrams)
- Held JAD sessions for internal Claims processing department
- Conducted requirement walkthroughs with the development and test teams before the development and testing phases respectively, to ensure that the requirements are accurately understood
- Created and maintained Requirements Traceability Matrix (RTM) to trace technical requirements to their business requirements and the test case to their functional requirements
- Gathered requirements and implemented Managed Care Medicare programs
- Actively participated in the Daily stand up and Weekly status meetings
- Design UAT test plans, test cases and test cases for integration, regression, and user acceptance testing (UAT) to improve overall quality of the system
- Prepared detailed user manuals and conducted training sessions.

Akshara Software Solutions - Junior Business Analyst Hyderabad • 10/2012 - 10/2014

- Gather requirements and interpreted information from multiple sources (including databases, interviews, etc.) and made recommendations based on the analysis
- Extensively used Agile Methodology in the process of the project management based on SDLC
- Used MS Word & Visio to document data flow of the AS-IS process and TO BE process
- · Managed work items in Microsoft Team Foundation Server
- Actively involved in Scrum Sprint Planning Sessions, Backlog Grooming, Sizing, Sprint Retrospectives & Reviews, Daily Standup, User Stories and Acceptance Criteria
- Documented scenarios for credit risk management for measuring, monitoring, and managing credit risk, thereby offering a broad range of analytical Capabilities and user control
- Participated in Task Creation, Task Estimation, and Task Distribution and Task Prioritization meetings
- Used JIRA for allotting task and issue tracking, user story management, and requirements traceability
- Prepared business requirements documentation (BRD), functional specifications documentation (FSD)
- Design UAT test plans, test cases and test cases for integration, regression, and user acceptance testing (UAT) to improve overall quality of the system
- Assisted business stakeholders with user acceptance testing, defect reporting and remediation
- Performed requirement analysis including data analysis and GAP analysis
- Worked on Rally for requirement tracking, issue tracking, and project management functions
- Interfaced with the client as part of the Requirements Engineering team to finalize the project scope
- Performed UI Design and Analysis, Involved in GUI interfacing and prototyping, System Integration testing and created test cases for QA Testing and test scripts.

DRIVING, KAYAKING, COOKING

Like to Explore by driving new places and food in my free time.